I love boxing because
it gave me health and I feel I get fit. And I feel young.
When I started here, I was very sick.
I has got asthma but now I am not sick anymore.
I haven't got the blood pressure anymore.
When I look at them boxing, I feel more energetic.
What I've realized - there is no age limit. You find that the more you exercise,
the more you feel younger. Boxing is not easy.
Their fists - they can knock you down. They are my super grannies.
Life Changing Episode - South Africa Boxing Grannies Testimony
Yes, Good morning, viewers and welcome to yet another life changing
episode of Changing Lives.
My name Anne and my name is Justin.
This is a platform where we have people who share how
God has rewritten the history of their lives
through an encounter with Jesus Christ at the SCOAN.
And today's episode will come with a punch.
A punch? - That's right - a punch, as we take the time to discover the inspiration
behind the phenomenon that you may have heard about recently
on international news - "South Africa's boxing grannies".
And guess who our guest today will be.
Tell them who it is: Claude Maphosa.
Good morning. It is well.
Welcome. Yes, he has gone from competing in body building competitions
to owning and running a gym. Not only focused on building better bodies
but also better communities.
But what inspired him to start such a unique program?
Well, let's hear how he was able to make a difference in this world
with what God put in his hands.
Life Changing Episode - South Africa Boxing Grannies Testimony
South Africa's Boxing Grannies
If somebody tries to attack me, I will punch him really -
really, I will hit him badly.
South Africa's Boxing Grannies
So now beat just number 1, 2...
So thank you very much for joining us on Changing Lives.
Please, tell us about yourself and what you do for a living.
It is an honour to be here. John Claude Maphosa.
Claude or Coach - they normally call me that way.
What I do currently is a fitness industry based on community development
through sport. Not only on physical but emotional and all that.
And tell us about your background in the fitness industry.
My background in the fitness industry - I was an athlete myself.
I started to do karate, went into body building which made me to be more
aware by people because I was one of the very few people that were trying
to represent South Africa at an early age,
that was in the juniors, in the seniors and in the world championships.
So by then, after I stopped, I realized that there was a lot because not so many people
had the opportunity I had. Not many youngsters from the
township can even get to my level
and I thought I must find a way on how to empower also the youth
to come into the industry. Not only in that department
but in every aspect of the department of being in the fitness industry.
Tell us, what was your situation like, before you encountered Prophet T.B. Joshua
and then your situation turned around.
At that particular time, one of my students
who saw that I was one of the best in the country at that time,
being just to compete in that level.
He introduced me to Emmanuel TV. His name was Harry.
And then at that time I didn't understand much.
It was not something that I could spend my time in.
Because if you are living worldly life, you are not focused on anything
else but yourself. And you don't realize that for you to step out of that life
to impact on people you need divine intervention.
And at that time when he gave me: "No, there is something that
I want you to do and watch". Because when you leave that industry,
you might have seen the world but you don't have the world in you.
You might be living and nobody will remember you.
Because that's why you see most of the people they say you had a legacy
but there is nothing to show of with.
Then he introduced me, I just went home and looked for the channel.
And it was very difficult then to even know the channel.
And then that's when it started. When I started watching, I realized
that is something a bit extraordinary and for you to help the community -
it's not what you know then, it's something different.
So I just glued and day by day I started, you know, getting interested.
Even my physical life had changed because being in an industry like that,
you diet a lot and your body can even give up
and there is a lot that goes on behind it.
So once you leave the sport, it's a little bit tough - it's a different lifestyle altogether.
That's when my life became to be different,
to be encouraged and not to selfabsorbing to myself
but to the society. That's where all it began.
And tell us, this new venture of yours that has propelled you
to the world map, so to say. Tell us, how did you encounter the prophet that
led to this remarkable breakthrough?
Amazing enough, before you see the prophet, you go to the Mountain,
and when you go to the Mountain for prayer, you'll find that this is unique place.
And then they tell you: "This is where the church started."
Now, you are open to see all these mountains, baboons and all the stuff
and then when they take you for a tour and this is the church you see - so big -
and they tell you: "This where it started", the thought is coming...
People around are working the whole day. You know, in your mind something
starts changing you, how you think. Because when you come, you're
thinking: "I want to get as much money as I want", -
thinking as other people out there. You see this small place -
eight people started it. You think: "No, that's humanly impossible".
You absorb all that within yourself and you start changing your way of thinking.
So when the opportunity to go to the SCOAN Prayer Mountain the first time came -
before I even met the Prophet then. They start showing you
the beginning, the humble beginning - what you see on TV now is reality.
And only to see that you see a small room, this room is quite big - and eight people.
And you're thinking to yourself: "How is it possible for somebody to
start in that - and then tomorrow we are here from all over the world
to encounter that?" So that kept me absorbed in my mindset.
When we finished prayers, I said: "No, I really want to see what exactly is going on".
South African Boxing Grannies
Let's go!
I love boxing because it keeps me healthy and I get fit and I feel young.
South African Boxing Grannies
When I started here, I was very sick. I had asthma.
But now I'm not sick anymore.
I am not taking any tablets. I am healthy. I'm ok.
I haven't got blood pressure anymore.
South African Boxing Grannies
When I had the opportunity to meet with man of God,
and in the office - obviously, at first I was hoping that I show him everything
that I wanted him to see in my plans and all that you know.
And only to find that he said: "No I'm aware of what you have".
And it was like a prophesy that - what you wanna do,
is not normal and at the same time what you think you gonna do
is not gonna be exactly what is going to happen.
Because then, I was thinking I was going to have the best gyms in the world -
that's what I came for.
I was not thinking because in our industry you are thinking of how to make
a person look in a certain manner because I'm a judge
of all the fitness industry - so we are looking at the perfect body in life.
So that's what you thinking of. And when he said what I'm gonna do is totally
not even the government can do that - I had no idea what he was talking about.
And it's not exactly what I wanted to hear.
I just wanted to hear something different but then I embraced what he said
and he gave me Morning Water to pray about it.
He said: "No, I will support you but it's not gonna be ordinary".
And then I embraced that. I took it and - the rest was just something else.
Ok, so after your receiving the prophesy you went back to South Africa,
you started a new fitness centre in a remote township, not even in the city -
in a remote township. And your first customers were grannies.
How were you able to relate the prophet's message with that situation?
And how did that help you to motivate you to believe in your dream?
Before I went to that one, I was in a different one
where normally that side - it was more of an urban way where people can come in.
And then when something told me, there is a place that is in the township
and there is no one there that has ever done these gym communities.
So I spoke to the community center and all of a sudden they said: "Ok, you can.
Come through." So I left the other side.
When I went there, obviously, there was no one in the gym and what not.
And they just gave me a place and they didn't give me a building.
So I had to think: "Ok, this is how I am going to do it. It's not a big gym
but this is how I'm gonna do it." And when I was doing renovations,
the people that caught the attention were grannies.
These grannies - they were about 15 to 20 of them.
And I was thinking I still had to do my marketing there.
I still had to do A, B, C but then I saw these grannies asked me:
"We wanna come and gym." I thought to myself: "God, is this another test now?"
Because these people, I mean some of them - they couldn't walk.
Some of them had problems. You can see...
They stayed in RDP houses and they were pensioners.
So I thought this had to be a test. But I said: "But I have been to the prayer mountain".
Immediately if anything goes wrong,
I will just try and phone and say: "Hey, I have got grannies, what will I do?"
But by that time something told me: "No, give them an opportunity."
Already I thought: "Ok, now I've got 20 members, I must register them.
I don't have to look for members." But that for some reason gave me motivation
to think and go back. When I watched Emmanuel TV, I thought
maybe this was a way of what I have been told to do.
South African Boxing Grannies
If somebody tries to attack me, I will punch him really.
Really I will hit him badly.
South African Boxing Grannies
For now it's just number 1, 2.
Right now we've got more than about 30 ladies. We take them from 60 and above.
On your guard!
South African Boxing Grannies
I like boxing. Whenever I train, I feel younger. I don't get pains. I feel good.
I have never trained somebody that is old.
I have always thought they are fragile.
Only to realize that there is more to them and there is more to what they
wanted to do. So I gave them opportunity and they ended up training me
instead of me training them because their energy level was just to high.
South Africa Boxing Grannies
I thought, now I have got members in the gym but yet when we look at RDP,
it's a rural development, it's a free government - these are
people from... we call them pensioners from 55 upwards.
So at that particular time now you are thinking: "Ok, I have spent a lot of money
to build this now. Obviously, you can not charge these people.
And maybe this is the way I can also give back."
So I registered them twice a week
but then I needed more anointing because some of the limbs were broken.
Everything looked shaky - and I am not a healer.
Obviously, I am a fitness person, so if you have got 20-30 grannies
and the ones are broken, you need 20 instructors to do that.
So by the grace of God... But what I have been taught
and considered - I had to follow the principles.
So in my small establishment we started...
Everyday I had to start with a prayer, I had to pray to God.
Morning Water that I have been given - practice to pray
because it's not normal anymore, it's not ordinary -
you're looking at things differently now. And then each and every day
they started coming and to my surprise, when I met the old ladies,
when I asked them: "Emmanuel!", they said: "God Is With Us".
I was shocked because this is a place where there is no DSTV:
"How do they know all that?" Because I learnt later on but they seemed to know.
So half of them had an idea. So it made my belief very easy.
So each and every day we trained, each and everyday we did
what together, we prayed.
And then every time there is birthday, they sing a birthday message
to the Prophet and that kept us to be unique as a family.
At the same time they must go home, you have to feed them as well.
But that became a motivation.
And when I came again and said to Prophet, he said: "No, keep doing what you're doing.
I am aware of that and we are in prayer."
And on his last birthday now this year, we kept on doing what he has
asked us to do.
And that's when things just changed.
For me to think "ok" from what I was doing to what it is now,
to call it totally different because you don't expect
somebody from China to call and say: "I am aware of what you are doing".
And you are thinking: "Maybe that's another test.
What am I doing?" He said: "No, I have seen boxing Grannies."
I said: "Ok, that's a little bit strange", but I said: "No problem."
Local newspapers, they wanna interview.
So it's almost looking at about 5 to 10 interviews.
And now I said to myself - we will do what we do all the time.
Whether you come and you wanna interview, we will carry on what we been assigned.
So each and every day it's like a museum now.
Those grannies, even if you look at them now, the way they punch -
it's something unique,
it's something that is different. And for me, I still have to absorb it
because I haven't had time to rest.
And everyday somebody else wants to know.
And even they are sitting in their houses,
sometimes I have to set up an interview
with BBC Yorkshire, with BBC Preston
and I have to give my "gogos" to speak,
whether you can hear their language or not but you interact with them.
So it's an amazing grace that keeps you wondering.
If you encounter Man Of God, he tells you that what you're doing is unique
but you need to be into prayer, you need to maintain
and when it's happening, sometimes you're still not understanding
where and how and what is...
Because these are not normal people that come to you.
Not one day we ever even applied for anything.
But the mere fact of someone out there telling you that he is praying with you
and the mere fact of you - whenever you are watching Emmanuel TV -
you feel at home. I don't have to come this side all the time.
But whatever I have been taught - and we do that and we practice that -
and today it's just something different.
And as you can see even from their testimonies.
When the grannies start speaking, I have never had a clue
that this is what has been going on.
Because I train them for 1 hour plus maybe 10 or 15 minutes,
give them something to eat. Then next program is something else,
so when people come now to testify or you hear on TV,
when they are playing on CNN, I hear: "I had cancer, I had this".
For me it's a surprise because I am thinking, how is that possible.
How is it possible for the person who enters here?
Sometimes, if they want Morning Water, I have to put it in a bottle
and say: "Go, do ABC", - and they follow that.
So it's amazing. You can't explain it.
Only God can explain it on my behalf.
South Africa Boxing Grannies
You were saying something. You said the last time you came during the
Prophet's Birthday, like Prophet T.B. Joshua's birthday -
was there any spectacular thing he spoke about giving at that time,
that you know further propelled your giving spirit sort of?
With the Prophet... if you watch Emmanuel TV - all you see, is him giving.
And sometimes when you meet the Prophet, you wanna speak to him
the whole day because when you come
you are thinking you gonna speak to the Prophet all day.
The minute you enter there, the presence that you feel -
even if he didn't talk to you or spoke to you,
there is something you absorb within yourself inside.
There is another voice that you carry along with you.
So most of the times it's what you see around you
and what you see when you get home, what you see when you just open the channel -
all you see is giving back
and nothing else. And then you start wondering how does he do it.
And when you apply that same principal, I have never applied for any of this people.
I have never even sent an application to say: "Come".
When I sent an application, they might not even look at it.
But funny enough, the last testimony
I had, I sent an application to another company, one company.
And I said: "I wanna do something for the grannies".
And that person said: "No, not now, we are fully".
And within the same day on one of our networks, the owner of the company
said to me: "Please, I wanna interview you.
I wanna have you on our platform."
Even now they have already put that program there.
But this other person said to me: "No, we are not..."
So I realized that what God can do, no man can stop you.
On the Prophet's birthday, he said:
"Please, spend time with people that are less fortunate than...
If you wanna for my birthday".
And that is the only way to honour him
rather than whatever gift because he can get any gift from...
But the greatest gift is to honour those less privileged than you. Be it people in the streets,
the homeless, the people that don't have what we have.
So that was one of those breakthroughs that came through
where everybody just started coming to want to know what is going on.
And then that also inspired me to realise that these are the people you spend time with
but yet again their fortune is changed to something different.
If you gonna start having international people, even your local people don't even know.
I mean my local - those who have came through but not to this level.
They are so shocked to see it on TV. They are so shocked that sitting there,
they start wondering where is this happening. But it's just right in the RDP Houses.
So that also transformed what he had said
that I will see amazing things happening in my life.
I will say it's amazing because like the Prophet rightly says that when we give,
we are planting seeds that will be multiplied back to us,
treasures in Heaven that faileth not and a burst that will never grow old.
And he says: "When you give, you are like unto God Who gives to all and receives from none."
So definitely when you give, God Himself will continue to supply.
Amen.
So as you follow the instructions of the Man of God to help the less privilleged,
help the elderly through -
do you feel you have discovered what God has called you to do
with this fitness centre in helping the elderly?
And how does it make you feel that the lives of the people that are coming -
they are being changed?
I feel like we can still do more. I feel like I am still learning.
Because every time I switch it on - I'm watching 24/7. I sleep watching Emmanuel TV.
You get to know things differently.
You get to see the gap in life, the people that you don't think of,
you feel like you are in training.
So presently, I still feel like I'm in training and maybe...
But I still feel like I'm in training.
And I'm still being trained as well because it's not an easy thing,
you need Divine intervention most definitely to know the direction.
Because the magnitude, them themselves - we still find it normal.
But only when somebody comes and says: "This is what you have done,
this is what is going on. This is what is changing our lives."
I'm not taking any tablets. I'm healthy. I am ok. I haven't got blood pressure anymore.
South Africa Boxing Grannies
And presently, giving back in this magnitude and realising that
these old ladies are going home and everytime they are looking forward to the gym,
it gives me peace of heart. It gives me something to look forward for myself.
Even if I'm down, I know that somebody out there needs me,
somebody out there needs something from me.
And them, giving testimonies of: "I don't go to the doctor anymore,
my limbs feel a little bit better", if I don't go to the gym and workout,
even my life at home is not as good as it.
And them, be able to do what they normally can not do - that is giving me
a lot of encouragement.
Wow. You have said so much but I want to ask you -
what impact has your dream and your vision got on the international community
today, knowing that the elderly ones in society
are always subjected to life of seclusion?
So what impact has it had on international communities?
Like you said, people have been calling you from all over the world
that they just want to visit your gym just to see those grannies who are
kicking and boxing?
This is overwhelming and to be known, to be one of those fitness coach
or that small A-team gym - it's amazing and it's hard to even think of
because these are not your normal TV stations,
these are breaking news.
And on top of that they are talking about what is happening internationally
at that particular time.
And all of a sudden, they are playing a clip about your boxing grannies
and you as well as a person, so it's quite enormous,
it's quite overwhelming and it's something that you can not explain.
Only God can explain. It's quite something different.
Because as a person who thought: "Ok, I will just be in my industry",
you never thought to go across the board.
Yes, you wanted to do that but not to this magnitude now.
So tell us, countries that have been visiting you so far
to see you since you introduced this?
Two German TV networks and the biggest one in Germany.
We've got France, we have got CGTN that is central.
We have got CCTV China, we have got the Swedish network.
We have got BBC - almost all the BBC Africa.
We have got the Middle East, Alejeezera.
And some of them, USA today - they are just taking all the clips together.
You have got each and everyone wanting the story.
I can not even go beyond that because
they are being inspired with what these grannies have done.
So, some of them - they are international.
Locally, they've been to 405 networks. They were just on the studio now.
They have been to all the radio stations, almost all the radio stations
speaking healthy life. And you talking of
the biggest radio stations in South Africa.
And at a particular time where people buy a slot - they don't even buy in slots.
So that is being very magnitude.
To God be the Glory, that's absolutely incredible
and your fitness centre helping the elderly has been a source of inspiration
for people all around the world. So what is your advice for people
who are close to the elderly anywhere around the world.
What will be your advice to them?
My first advice is to stay connected to Emmanuel TV - it will change your life.
And for some of us, we are still learning how to go about it
and you need someone that has been there and knows exactly
because taking care of our old ladies is not an easy thing.
And it's never been heard of, it's tough because most of the youth now...
Maybe they are taking care of their grand kids, they go to live life.
But you don't realise that those are the people who can change your life.
If you honour them.
Those are the people that you can not take for granted.
Because they have so much to give, and if you don't give to them,
they will give the blessings to someone.
Because these are ordinary people being placed in a home
where not even anybody visits them but the mere fact of now even adverts -
people want to do movies, people want to do ABC
based on their livestyle. So you can imagine what's gonna happen to them
because they are being seen all over the world
and these are the same people that you lived with.
And somebody saw the opportunity and said: "Don't throw them out".
So they are changing not only everybody's life, even their family's life.
Those who had thought: "No, this is just..." They have done a lot,
quite a lot.
And that's like Prophet T.B. Joshua has been saying that as you help the less privileged,
as you help the elderly in your community, you'll begin to discover
yourself and what God has called you to do and that's exactly what has been happening in your life as well.
Most definitely.
All I can say now, meeting Man of God, having an opportunity to sit with him
and also for him what he said, it has come to pass.
The prophesy that he said that what I do, is not going to be ordinary,
and obviously, it's gonna be something that is unheard of -
now it has come to pass in a manner that no matter what
happens, people are aware that to change somebody's life
you have to look after the elderly. And for me, I don't take that for granted,
no matter the circumstances.
Fantastic. Well, we have got some questions from some viewers around
the world that have been inspired by what you are doing. So we quickly
read them out for you.
Here Claude, we have questions for you from our viewers.
First question comes from Irene who stays in Luxembourg.
And she says: "I love your work,
and how God is using you to impact people's lives so wonderfully.
How can I support it?"
Most definitely, I will say - look around you and visit the elderly.
It has to start within and we will also support you in every way we can,
if you need assistance, we can always be there to come and advice
because it takes one with a big heart and the heart has to be from God.
And if it's not from God, you can do it for today but tomorrow when challenges come, it's not easy.
And it's something that for that person in Luxembourg to see what is happening.
Obviously, she has already been touched,
so that's one of the things I can say.
And we are open to any help we can
and we would also like to spread to other places to advice where we can
and to say those who are interested in doing A,B,C. But most importantly around you
you will see that there is somebody in need - that's where you can also start.
That's a wonderful advice. I believe Irene is listening to you right now. She is pleased.
So we got another question from the viewers. It's from Mavis, she is from Scotland.
She says: "I am old woman of 76 years old, I have been very inspired by your program.
I always stay at home. Rarely going out and engaging in outdoor activities because of the cold weather.
What advice would you give me?"
Cold weather is actually an advantage
because once you start taking the gloves, as you can see, you start sweating.
So that would be one of those things that can even motivate you more.
It's not like us here, where it's hot and already our metabolism and our system is already fired up.
So wherever she is, I mean it's just a matter of getting out of that comfort zone.
And be able to say "no" one or two. You don't have to start saying: "I'm going to break a bone today."
It's once a day you wake up in the morning, you do what you have to do
and even on nutrition side we advice as well that you don't have to eat so much or whatever it is.
You wake up in the morning, you eat your garlic and ginger, that will wake you up.
If you are not having people around you. And then after that you just eat your apple
and what just to sustain your energy level.
So that also gives you an encouragement.
And even on our platform, our boxing grannies, every Tuesday, Thursday - if you go to their facebook page,
you will see what they did today. So we try and encourage to say - they are doing it.
And it's not that they started today - they have been doing it for a while.
You follow them - they couldn't walk but now they are walking. And wherever she is, she shouldn't be discouraged.
Just being around them and see what they do and that will keep her going as well.
Thank God. Wonderful advice, we believe Mavis is listening wherever she is and that will inspire her
to get the boxing gloves on.
Most definitely. Thank you.
We thank God for the inspiration He has given you. Emmanuel, thank you.
South Africa's Boxing Grannies
If somebody tries to attack me, I will punch him really. Really, I will hit him badly.
Now it's just gonna be 1, 2.
Right now we have got more than about 30 ladies, we take them from 60 and above.
On your guard, gogo. Don't forget, on your guard.
I like boxing. Whenever I train, I feel young. I don't get pains, I feel good.
South Africa's Boxing Grannies
I have never trained somebody that is old. I have always thought they are fragile.
Only to realise that there is more to them and there is more to what they wanted to do, so I gave them opportunity.
And they ended up training me instead of me training them because their energy level was just too high.
South Africa's Boxing Grannies
Well, Coach Claude, we have seen the South African Boxing Grannies and are absolutely impressed
with their skills and the training that you have been giving them.
But it's a shame that there is no grannies around here that you could give a demonstration for.
Come on, wait a minute. Do you need a granny here? I'm here.
Let's do it. We've got Annie.
Lets see how the grannies do it.
So all the way to Luxembourg.
So Irene, let's show you how we do it.
So the most important part, obviously you don't start with your...
You just start of with your warm up. You take this hand and you put it on the other side.
You just punch there, that's 1, 2, right. You can punch twice 1,2 and then you go 3,3.
But always make sure that when you punch, you're always on your guard.
Your hands are up, right. What it means - when your hands are up like this, it is locked, no matter what happens -
nothing comes, nothing happens to you. So when you punch, you just punch 1, punch again.
And then on your guard. So punch again - on your guard.
So now, what you do - if you don't wanna guard, maybe I wanna punch your back.
So you punch 1, punch and then you just dodge.
Right, 1, 2 and then I just go down, 1, 2. So obviously, what you are doing now - it is also part of stretching.
Right. So you just go 1, 2. Then I go, then you say 2 twice. 1,2.
1,2. This is interesting.
Maybe he wants to 1 or 2 times there.
He is a grandpa. This will be awesome.
Viewers around the world, we've got some lessons from Coach Claude.Take some notes.
So instead I will ask you to face the other side now, we wanna do something different.
Ok. Right, 1, 2. - This is what the grannies are doing?
1,2. So I can still go down. 1,2. Up 1,2. So at the same time, as you can see,
it's part of your stretching. - I can feel in the back. It's really stretching the back.
It's very good. So those are some of the things that you can also do at home.
Alright, thanks coach Claude, for the demonstration and the lesson.
Thank you. You are more than welcome.
Thank you for joining us on Changing Lives.
Thank you. It is well.
Thank you so much for coming. Thank you.
South Africa's Boxing Grannies
Lets go.
I love boxing because it keeps me healthy and I feel I get fit and I feel young.
South Africa's Boxing Grannies
Viewers, thank you so much for joining us. We believe that you have been encouraged by Claude's testimony.
Knowing that each day, as we overcome our challenges, we make history
and then fulfill our destinies thereby.
Therefore, if God gives you a vision and it is opposed by men, please, do not reduce your vision.
But stay in the will of God.
Also be encouraged to know that whatever you have in your hands today,
is enough to create the future that God has promised you.
But you know what - a seed can not multiply, unless it is planted.
One fundamental lesson we take from Claude's life experience is that those who are placed on a horse,
should not forget those who can not ride on a donkey.
And this simply means that the privileged should remember the less privileged.
Therefore viewers, what do you have to give? It could be your time,
it could be your love, it could be your smile, it could be your finances,
it could even be your boxing gloves. I mean, every good thing that God has given you -
find those who need you and build your life around your contribution to others.
So where are your elderly ones? Look for them. Find them and care for them
and you will reach old age.
We thank you very much for joining us on this episode of Changing Lives. From me, Justin,
and from me, Ann - remain blessed.
South Africa's Boxing Grannies
You know this guy, we love him so much, Claude is everything in our lives.
He is a good coach. I hope he will be here forever. Because without him maybe I wouldn't be here by this time.
South Africa's Boxing Grannies
Boxing is not easy, but what they do is super awesome.
Punching, their fists - they can knock you down.
They are my super grannies.
South Africa's Boxing Grannies
TT Monica Asefa 03/07/18 RV: Pavel Tatyana Zheleznyakov 17/08/2018